FIRST LAST

QUALITY ASSURANCE SPECIALIST

Bay Area, California • +1-234-456-789 • professionalemail@resumeworded.com • linkedin.com/in/username

SUMMARY

QA Analyst with three years of experience working on a wide range of platforms with excellent understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Testing cycle (STLC). Led teams of 5-15 people across technology and design departments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Resume Worded, New York, NY QA Analyst

May 2020 – Present

- Created key metrics and audit processes to ensure established goals were met, accomplishing a QAS score on key metrics of 99.6%.
- Evaluated and implemented solutions to improve efficiency and quality, reducing IT workload by 20%.
- Created test scripts and test cases for 10+ new applications, ensuring 100% compliance with standards.
- Developed and executed detailed automated regression testing using automation testing tool SeeTest
- Automated multiple business processes for early market ready, leading to 14.5% increase in sales productivity.

Growthsi, New York, NY

July 2019 – May 2020

QA Analyst (One Year Placement Program)

- Conducted Black box testing on bluetooth connectivity profiles of embedded systems with 95% success rate working on Windows Mobile, Android and iOS platforms.
- Streamlined procedures with current organization practices and as per standard practice, reducing processing time by 60%.
- Mentored and led a team of 9 peers, successfully delivering the WCMS Project on time and 2 weeks ahead of schedule.

Third Company, San Diego, CA Junior QA Analyst (Co-op Program)

June 2018 – July 2019

- Designed and developed over 200 UI automation tests and over 500 unit tests.
- Worked efficiently on mobile and web applications on both iOS and Android platforms, leading 2 global major platform updates and more than 100 operational system changes.

EDUCATION

Resume Worded University, San Francisco, CA

July 2019

Master of Engineering — Business Management and IT

- Awards: Resume Worded Teaching Fellow (only 5 awarded to class), Dean's List 2012 (Top 10%)
- Relevant Courses: Data Science, Linear Algebra, Designing functional programs.
- Completed one-year study abroad with Singapore University

SKILLS & OTHER

Skills: Selenium, Backbone.js, Blackboard software, Google AngularJS, SeeTest, UFT, ASP.NET Core MVC, React, Redux, Puppeteer, Browser Automation, Regression Testing, Penetration Testing

Volunteering: Volunteered and led development of 2IT Projects for the local Red Cross Chapter, 4 month tenure.